JUSTIN VELANDER HOLT

justin@onthecodeagain.com | +1-312-568-6632 | Chicago, IL

onthecodeagain.com | linkedin.com/in/velander | github.com/justinvholt

COVER LETTER

Dear Hiring Manager,

For the past five years I literally donated my body to science for the purpose of getting out of debt and saving up tuition to acquire a new skill set. I crisscrossed the country countless times in pursuit of clinical trials. I navigated my way through downpours and blizzards, spin outs and wrecks, professional rejection and personal heartbreak. All-too-frequent 21+ hour drives. 250+ days per year in a controlled environment doing not-so-hard time. (Think of living in a dorm with labs attached.) Thousands of blood draws for the hope of medical breakthroughs and a sizable nest egg.

Simply, it's a been a bizarre and contentious journey to even begin learning code.

But learn code I did. After three years of online tutorials, one-on-one mentoring, a handful of open-source projects and a 9-week intensive boot camp in Rio de Janeiro, I am certainly ready to launch a career as a full stack developer. I've done a lot of growing on my own, but now I'm seeking a team to take me beyond the tinkering stage and keep me on the right path. I'm seeking secure employment and glowing references, and I'm determined to put in the due diligence to earn both. I intend to bridge this gap between learning and doing by giving my focus and dedication to those who will take a chance on me.

I've worked so hard just to get here. I'm looking forward to traveling farther, working smarter, living brighter.

Quo imus, Justin Holt

JUSTIN VELANDER HOLT

justin@onthecodeagain.com | +1-312-568-6632 | Chicago, IL

onthecodeagain.com | linkedin.com/in/velander | github.com/justinvholt

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Junior web developer on the cusp of a long-awaited career launch. I've spent three years studying code and building apps while living on the road. 170,000 miles and many git pushes later I am ready to join a team and establish a solid reputation as a dependable, diligent and accomplished full stack developer.

US Citizen · Open to Relocation · Available to Start Immediately

SKILLS

- Ruby
- Javascript
- Ruby on RailsHTML
- CSS

- SQL • Bootstrap
- Java Linux
- Python Github
- ReactJSHeroku
- ¡Query

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer (Freelance) | OnTheCodeAgain.com

12/2017 - Present

Freelance/open-source web development. Notable projects include:

- On the Code Again (2019) Personal web site portfolio; built with Ruby, Javascript, ¡Query and Ruby on Rails.
- Chronos (2018) Automated laytime management system to assist with processing late fees for cargo shipping; built with Ruby, Javascript, ¡Query and Ruby on Rails. Tasked with allowing users to edit and save information within the view page for easier navigation. Later oversaw front-end continuity and button design.
- dopcast (2018-2019) Comprehensive podcast search engine; built with Ruby, Javascript and Ruby on Rails. Currently assisting founder with second iteration of app that will allow for faster loading time and easier navigation.
- BFN Networks (2000-2014) Podcasting network site. Three versions of site have been built and maintained using HTML, CSS, XML, Wordpress and Bootstrap.

Auditor (Contract) | Phase 1 Medical Trials

03/2016 - 06/2019

 Collating and organizing paperwork for individual Phase I medical trials for facilities nationwide, ensuring accuracy and compliance per pharmaceutical drug sponsors' guidelines

EDUCATION

Le Wagon – Rio de Janeiro, BR

2018

Certification: Web Development

- 9-week intensive coding boot camp specializing in full stack development Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SQL, Javascript, iQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Linux, Github and Heroku
- Team lead and demo presenter for capstone project: https://youtu.be/W0UOC5IJ4wo?t=400

University of Illinois at Chicago - Chicago, IL, USA

2003

Bachelor of Arts: Creative Writing